Carlo Rosso

Computer Science Student

☑ carlorosso02@gmail.com 🏫 danesinoo.github.io

About me _____

Passionate Computer Science Master's student with hands-on experience in machine learning and software development. My enthusiasm was solidified during the internship, when I explored and understood state-ofthe-art machine learning algorithms and architectures. Currently, I am seeking a two-year student job position in the IT field

Professional Experience _____

Machine Learning Intern

Padua (PD), Italy

University of Padua

07/2024 - 08/2024

- Sentiment analysis on SST-5 dataset.
- Compared Kernel Methods, RNN and LLMs.

Front Office Assistant

Padua (PD), Italy

University of Padua

08/2023 - 11/2023

Data processing support, front office tasks.

Mechanical Worker

Motta di Livenza, Italy

TPA Srl

06/2019 - 07/2019

Fabricated and assembled automated machines.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

University of Copenhagen

09/2024 - ongoing

- Interesting courses: Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, Machine Learning, Integrative Structural Biology.
- GPA: 2.5

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Padua

09/2021 - 09/2024

- Final Grade: 106/110.
- GPA: 3.5

Exchange Student

Vejle, Denmark

Rødkilde Gymnasium

08/2019 - 05/2020

The year of the COVID-19 pandemic.

Projects _____

Somebody's Blog! Anywhere in the World

Personal Project

ongoing

- Personal development blog.
- · Technologies: Markdown, Rust, Workflow.
- · Infrastructure to convert markdown into HTML.

Weav

Friends Project

maybe done

- Cross-platform social media.
- Backend: Python, Django, gRPC, TypeScript.
- Frontend: TypeScript, React-Native, Redux.

Easy Meal

Software Engineer, University of Padua

done

- Web app to manage orders of restaurateurs.
- · Technologies: Docker, Nest.js, Drizzle ORM, PostgreSQL and Angular.
- Evaluation: 25/30.

Music vs Robot

Object-Oriented Programming, University of Padua

done

- Tower-defense-style game.
- C++14 with Qt framework.
- Separation of concerns for maintainability.
- · Evaluation: 3/3 with honors.

Spoken Languages _____

Italian Native

English Fluent, IELTS 7.5

Danish Basic, (Work in progress)

Latin Only reading, Love the poetry

Skills

Machine NLP, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn,

Learning Pandas, Numpy, HuggingFace

Programming Python, Haskell, Rust, Java, C++, C, Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, Golang, SQL,

Html, Typst, LaTex, Lua, Matlab

Tools Algorithms, Functional Programming,

Git, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Database, Web Development

Interests _____

Sports Judo, Sailing, Skiing, Climbing

Hobbies Cooking, Open Source, Curiosity, Music,

Reading, 3D Modeling